SUMMARY

People-oriented computer science enthusiast with a couple of project experiences. Accumulated work experiences in different fields. Independent and self-motivating in learning new programming languages and concepts. Passionate in implementing current knowledge to solve problems that will stimulate growth for the company and myself.

EDUCATION

Universiti Sains Malaysia

September 2018 - Present

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours) (Software Engineering)

Minor : Mathematics

CGPA : 3.79 (First Class Honours, as of Year 4 Semester 1)

MUET : Band 5

TECHNICAL (IT) SKILLS

Programming Languages

- C++
- Java
- Python
- Ruby
- Rails
- SQL
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PHP

Project Experiences

- Designed, built, and documented a webpage using HTML/CSS/JavaScript/PHP.
- Planned, designed, and programmed a community-oriented application using Java for *Google Solutions Challenge* 2020.
- Created and documented a mock web-based database software using SQL in Oracle Application Express.
- Developed and programmed a productivity-game hybrid application using Java for an assignment.
- Designed, analyzed, and prototyped mock systems using system analysis diagrams such as state diagrams, use case diagrams, and activity diagrams.

WORK EXPERIENCES

CoinGecko, Software Engineering Intern

March 2021 - August 2021

- Accomplished 100+ tasks as measured by Basecamp tickets, by working as full stack.
- Revamped CoinGecko's careers and developer's API page, following Adobe XD guide, using Tailwind and Bootstrap.
- Implemented multiple exchanges into CoinGecko for aggregation, by using GraphQL and REST API.
- Ensure code is maintainable and clean by writing Rspec tests and running test cases.
- Picked up Ruby and Ruby on Rails in the span of 2 months, by reading and working on external projects.

SellByTel Group, Virtual Demand Generation Specialist

March 2018 - July 2018

- Generated sales for Hewlett-Packard (HP) products mainly for Singapore and Malaysia market.
- Educated customers on the latest security features on HP products, especially printers.
- Consulted and advised companies on their IT setup.
- Collaborated with colleagues of different nationalities and cultures.
- Trained in computer hardware knowledge and soft skills.
- Communicated in multiple languages daily with Singaporean and Malaysian customers.

CO-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

USM Bridge and Chess Club, Member

September 2018 - June 2020

- Organized numerous events in USM to ensure positive cashflow for the club.
- Adapted self to skillsets such as poster design and photography for club events.
- Participated in organizing the International Chess Open Tournament, which is the hallmark of the club.

AIESEC, Member (iGV)

September 2018 - June 2019

- Interviewed potential volunteers from across the globe and determine volunteers who are fit to volunteer in Penang for *Project Speak Up*.
- Facilitated the global volunteers during their stay in Penang.
- Collaborated with other departments to ensure the growth of AIESEC in Penang.

INVOLVEMENTS/ ACHIEVEMENTS

- National Top 10 for ASEAN Data Science Explorer (ADSE) 2020.
- Organizing Committee Marketing for Fall National Induction Leadership Conference 2019.
- Organizing Committee Publicity for International-Penang Pesta Hoki 2018.
- Organizing Committee Arbiter for USM Chess Open Tournament International 2019.
- Project director for various events under USM Bridge and Chess Club.

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

Proficient in Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Microsoft Visio, IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Dev-C++, SAP Analytics, Adobe XD. Beginner in Adobe Illustrator and Premiere Pro.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Trilingual in English, Chinese & Malay. Beginner in Japanese and Korean.

OTHERS

GitHub : DanielChang98 Code Forces : danielchang98